Avram Eisner

Front End Web Developer

4130 38th Ave SW Seattle, WA 98126 (206) 214-8363 avrame@gmail.com

www.avrameisner.com www.github.com/avrame www.linkedin.com/in/avrame

PROFILE

From the moment I witnessed my first website slowly render on a 14.4k modem at age 13, I was captivated by the web's potential. For the past 18 years, I have worked as a front end web developer at a variety of different companies, and my passion and drive to innovate in this exciting medium has never waned. The thrill of this ever-evolving field continues to drive me. Let's explore the next chapter together!

SKILLS

JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Redux, Jest, HTML, CSS, Git

EXPERIENCE

Persefoni Al Inc, Seattle, WA - Senior Front End Web Developer

MAY 2022 - AUGUST 2023

Technologies used: React, Next.js, TypeScript, Radix UI, Jest, Playwright

- Spearheaded the development of components in Persefoni's Kore UI library, including charts, graphs, and filterable tables.
- Led the delivery of the Scope Three data-exchange tool, enabling companies to request emission data from suppliers and clients.
- Streamlined code organization by creating new packages within the web-app mono-repo to consolidate i18n and data-fetching code, resulting in improved maintainability and efficiency.

D-Wave, Seattle, WA - Senior Front End Web Developer

OCTOBER 2020 - APRIL 2022

Technologies used: React, Redux, Jest, Babel, Webpack

- Solely developed the Leap admin site front-end, enhancing project and user management efficiency.
- Created an accessible React component library using functional components with hooks.
- Implemented front-end security measures to prevent XSS attacks and SQL injection.

Verizon Media (Contract), Seattle, WA - Front End Web Developer

JUNE 2020 - OCTOBER 2020

Technologies used: React, Redux, Three.js, GraphQL, AWS Amplify

- Built an augmented reality web app to facilitate authoring and sharing of AR content.
- Successfully migrated codebase from JavaScript to TypeScript for improved reliability.
- Developed custom code to optimize GLTF and GLB model file handling.

Disney (Contract), Seattle, WA - Front End Web Developer

AUGUST 2019 - APRIL 2020

Technologies used: React, Redux, Angular, Jest, Babel, Webpack

- Collaborated with a team to rewrite the OneID account system, enhancing the user experience across Disney properties.
- Improved the legacy universal account system by addressing UI issues and introducing new features.
- Facilitated cross-team collaboration to deliver multilingual functionality in over a dozen different languages.

Tesseract Software, Seattle, WA - Founder and Developer

MAY 2018 - JUNE 2020

Technologies used: Unity, C#, Git, Blender

- Created an educational VR app called You Are Here, showcasing the universe at various scales.
- Imported and managed extensive astronomical data, enriching user experience.
- Developed custom code for importing stars and galaxies from astronomical databases.

FLEXE, Seattle, WA - Front End Web Developer

MARCH 2017 - MAY 2018

Technologies used: React, TypeScript, Jest, Google Cloud, Git

- Spearheaded the development of FLEXE's React-based internal admin website, streamlining warehouse reservation processes.
- Migrated the new admin website to Google Cloud with automatic deployments to reduce time to deployment.

EDUCATION

University of Washington, Seattle, WA - Informatics, B.S.

SEPTEMBER 2002 - MAY 2005

Coursework included the study of information systems and technology with a human-centered approach: Information System Design, Computer Networks, Database Design, Information Retrieval Systems, Systems Analysis and Design, and Information Management